To import a trial into KDSmart, go to the Trials screen and select the Import button.
Select the Device option to choose a file on your KDSmart device.
Here you can select a file to import. In this example, we are importing a KDX file.
A KDX file can include a trial with any traits, tags, and scored data.
The trial will now be available on the Trials screen.
You can also import trials in CSV format.
KDSmart will guess what to import each column as. You will need to correct any errors.
When importing CSV trials, you will need to choose a trait instance style.
Select the Import button to import the trial. It will now be available on the Trials screen.
You can also import traits and tags from CSV files with the same method. See the KDSmart User Guides for more information about importing data.