Trials are usually imported, but you can also create new trials within the KDSmart app.
Go to the Trials screen and choose the Create Trial option from the Menu.
Enter the details such as the trial name
Here we are creating an X/Y trial with columns and rows and each plot has an x/y coordinate. We will demontrate Plot trials later in the video.
For X/Y trials, you need to choose the number of columns and the number of rows.
Optionally, you can add a number of subplots.
Choosing '2' here means that each plot in the trial will contain two subplots.
Choose a trait instance style to determine how instances of the same trait are shown.
Select the Confirm button when you are ready to create the trial.
It will now appear on the Trials screen and you can select it to add more details.
Select the Edit button for traits to add traits to the trial.
Add trait instances if you want to score the same trait multiple times.
Now we are going to create a Plot ID trial.
Plot ID trials contains plots with unique identification numbers.
Choose the number of plots you want in the trial.
The Run Length can be set to vertical or horizontal.
No subplots were added to the Plot ID trial.
Select the Add Subplot option from the Menu if you want to add them later.